Zoe: The sort of information that
should be kept confidential is
anything related to the child and
young person, anything that could be
perceived as personal, definitely, but
anything related to their education.
Kerry: Would be those that, from my
experience, it's things like around
toileting needs, medications, yeah.
any further diagnoses that the
young people might have, you
know, are only shared with those
people that it is relevant to,
to give them the better support.
Ellen: Their needs as well, because
every student has their own plan and
it tells us in there what their reading
ages are what their kind of development
is, mental, kind of development.
So all of that, we
would keep confidential.
We couldn't share that outside of here.
Zoe: Even if I'm having a
conversation with a child about
their experience in the classroom.
If I'm planning to pass that information
on, I'll always talk to the child and
check they're happy with me passing it on.
Phil: If it's me that identified that
a pupil needs to see, for instance,
a counselor or play therapist, they
may benefit from that, for instance,
due to a childhood trauma that
they need to process and play out.
I mean, I don't pretend to understand
the process entirely, but what I do know
is that that session is between them
and the play therapist or the counselor
for them to work out and it's led by
them and whilst people, other members
of staff supporting those people,
know that they may be attending these
sessions, the content is important too.